ANDREI CHIRITA

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

SUMMARY

I am a Full-stack web developer with a passion for programming and computer software & hardware. I have a strong background in software testing and have professionally developed with technologies such as Vue, Bootstrap, React, Node, and Firebase. Worked closely with professional developers in agile environments and work excellently individually and in a team environment.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES: JavaScript, Ruby, HTML, CSS

FRAMEWORKS, LIBRARIES & ENVIRONEMNTS: NodeJS, ReactJS, Ajax, Express, EJS, jQuery, Bootstrap, ActiveRecord, React Native, Ruby on Rails, SASS, TypeScript, VueJS, Firebase TESTING: Storybook, Cypress, RSpec, Jest, Mocha & Chai

SYSTEMS AND DATABASES: SQL, Git, MongoDB, Kubernetes, Docker

EMPLOYMENT

NextGen Kitchens, Full-stack Developer

Jan. 2024 - Apr. 2024

- Developed and maintained the Restaurant Manager application using Vue.js, prioritizing efficient front-end functionality and a modern layout for the website.
- Implemented real-time data synchronization and storage solutions with Firebase, creating and editing data layouts and tables when necessary on change requirements.
- Enforced code quality and consistency through the use of ESLint and Prettier, ensuring adherence to best practices and collaboration within the development team.
- Collaborated with developers on the front-end portion of the kiosk app that communicate through data stored via the Restaurant Manager in Firebase.
- Developed in an Agile environment with daily progress stand-ups, weekly sprint work allocation, bi-weekly sprint retrospectives and quarterly updates and planning for large scale objectives and deliverables.
- Remained up to date on industry trends and emerging technologies in the restaurant tech industry to incorporate automated and innovative solutions to the application. Examples of this include automated ordering for ingredients and automated alerts on expiry and mismatched data.
- Submitted pull requests in a github repository, utilizing branches for new features, Node usage for project set-up and installation, and git commands for the appropriate actions required (add, checkout, merge, commits).
- Wrote clean, maintainable code through the use of re-usable Vue components and mixins for repeat function calls. Utilized Sass where applicable for maintainable styling.

Sofvie Inc., Front-end Developer

Oct. 2023 - Dec. 2023

- Developed a user-friendly mobile-first technician application that streamlined the company's field operations. The application included processes such as service requests, monitoring equipment status, and logging essential data such as remainder of usability in their recyclable tanks.
- Utilized Bootstrap, HTML, and CSS to create a responsive user interface based on mock-ups from UI Designers where mobile phones were the primary device used. Scalability and use of the Bootstrap framework developing the website allowed for optimal desktop and mobile functionality.
- Implemented Javascript using React in order to enhance the application through the use of dynamic forms, real-time updates, and data validation. Various of the forms developed with bootstrap were further expanded on to include date pickers, back-end connection to the database, and redirection.
- Maintained the project's source code and collaborated with a cross-functional developer and management team using Git. Made use of my own individual branch on the project to maintain my portion, versions, and pull requests.
- Actively identified and resolved issues throughout the development process using VSCode Live Explorer to navigate and view web pages as I created new features and fixed existing ones.

Miipe Inc, QA Engineer

June 2019 - Oct. 2021

- Was the main tester for one of Bell's top 3 projects in 2020. Joining their largest database Maximo with their new router line. Tested the functionality of new devices being set up with newly built in-house technician software. Chosen as the main tester due to my strict attention to detail and simplicity of test cases, allowing simpler collaboration between the business, development and the QA Team.
- Extensive experience with defect tracking software such as Jira and Redmine.
- Use of SoapUI, Postman and Puppeteer to inject test scenarios and automate submissions.
- Developed a comprehensive test automation suite using Cypress and JavaScript, covering critical features of Bell's Alarm Tracking software. This led to a 40% reduction in manual regression testing efforts and significantly improved the software's stability.
- Taken part in numerous testing lifecycles such as End-to-End, User Acceptance Testing, Unit Testing and Regression Testing. Testing was executed on various Bell web and cloud systems such as their alarm tracking software, Maximo database, ticket creation and management software.
- Expanded in-house testing application with automated tests via Cypress for Bell's Alarm Tracking Software. Used Cypress in combination with Javascript to prioritize repetitive tests during end-to-end
- Mentored junior QA team members, providing training on best testing practices and standards. Increased the team's overall skillset and familiarity with Bell in-house products and became the go-to resource for the QA and Development team.
- Wrote and optimized SQL queries for data retrieval and manipulation. Developed knowledge in database management systems like MySQL and PSQL

PROJECTS

To-do List

A to do list app using React, Bootstrap, and local storage as a database to store amd access notes locally. Users can create, edit, remove, complete, and search for notes using various tags like title, description, category, and date.

Tech Stack:

React, React-Router, Bootstrap, UIDV4, Local Storage, Typescript

Website Portfolio

A website I designed for myself to showcase my skills and front-end capabilities, including projects and contact information.

Tech stack:

React, SASS, React-Router, Bootstrap, Animate on Scroll, Typewriter

EDUCATION

Lighthouse LabsDiploma Full-stack Web Development 2022

Sept. 2022 - Dec. 2022

June 2023